[{"question":"<p><b>Solve for p in this following equation given in base two. 11(p + 110) = 1001p<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["10","11","110","111"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>In a class, 37 students take at least one of chemistry, economics and government, 8 students take chemistry, 19 take economics and 25 take government. 12 students take economics and government but nobody takes chemistry and economics. How many students take both chemistry and government?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["3","4","5","6"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>A businessman invested a total of N200,000 in two companies which paid dividends of 5% and 7% respectively. If he received a total of N11,600 as dividends, how much did he invest at 5%?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["N160,000","N40,000","N120,000","N80,000"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>A cyclist rode for 30minutes at xkm\/hr. If the total distance covered is less than 60km, what is the range of values of x?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["x < 140","x < 120","x < 290","x < 280"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Z is a partly constant and partly varies inversely as the square of d. when d = 1, z = 11 and when d= 2, z= 10. Find the value of z when d = 4.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["2","9.75","5","5.75"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Factorize 16(3x + 2y)<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 25(a + 2b)<sup>2<\/sup><\/b><\/p>","options":["(12x + 8y + 5a + 10b) (12x + 8y - 5a - 10b)","(12x + 8y - 5a - 10b) (12x + 8y - 5a - 10b)","20(3x + 2y - a - 2b) (3x + 2y + a + 2b)","20(3x + 2y + a + 2b) (3x + 2y + a + 2b)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>A cone has a base radius 4cm and height 3cm. The area of its curved surface is<\/b><\/p>","options":["12 \u03c0cm<sup>2<\/sup>","24 \u03c0cm<sup>2<\/sup>","20 \u03c0cm<sup>2<\/sup>","15 \u03c0cm<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Expand the expression (x<sup>2<\/sup> -2x -3)(x<sup>2<\/sup> + x + 1)<\/b><\/p>","options":["x<sup>4<\/sup> \u2013 4x<sup>2<\/sup> - 5x \u2013 3","\u2013x<sup>3<\/sup> \u2013 4x<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 5x \u2013 3","x<sup>4<\/sup> \u2013 x<sup>3<\/sup> \u2013 4x<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 5x \u2013 3","x<sup>4<\/sup> \u2013 4x<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 5x \u2013 3"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>A girl walks 30m from a point P on a bearing of 040\u00b0 to a point Q. She then walks 30m on a bearing of 140\u00b0 to a point R. the bearing of R from P is<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["90\u00b0","50\u00b0","45\u00b0","40\u00b0"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>A regular polygon has each of its angles as 160\u00b0. What is the number of sides of the polygon?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["36","9","18","20"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>The interior angles of a pentagon are: 180\u00b0, 118\u00b0, 80\u00b0, 78\u00b0 and x. The value of x is:<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["84\u00b0","108\u00b0","120\u00b0","134\u00b0"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>All the vertices of an isosceles triangle lie on a circle and each of the base angles of the triangle is 65\u00b0. The angle subtended at the center of the circle by the base of the triangle is:<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["130\u00b0","115\u00b0","100\u00b0","65\u00b0"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>A square tile measures 20cm by 20cm. How many of such files will cover a floor measuring 5m by 4m.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["500","400","320","250"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>The volume of a certain sphere is numerically equal to twice its surface area. The diameter of the sphere is:<\/b><\/p>","options":["6","9","12","\u221a6"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>A bearing of 310\u00b0, expressed as a compass bearing is:<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["N50\u00b0W","N40\u00b0W","S40\u00b0E","S50\u00b0W"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>The average of the three children in a family is 9 years. If the average age of their parents is 39 years, the average age of the whole family is:<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["20 years","21 years","24 years","27 years"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Simplify 3 \u00f7 (1 + <sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub> of <sup>6<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub>)<\/b><\/p>","options":["<sup>8<\/sup>\/<sub>33<\/sub>","<sup>21<\/sup>\/<sub>11<\/sub>","<sup>33<\/sup>\/<sub>21<\/sub>","<sup>21<\/sup>\/<sub>8<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Evaluate x in base 3 if 41<sub>x<\/sub> \u2013 22<sub>x<\/sub> = 17<sub>x<\/sub><\/b><\/p>","options":["11","8","12","22"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>A woman buys 4 bags of rice for \u20a656 per bag and 3 bags of beans for \u20a626 per bag using the currency \u201cNAIRA\u201d (\u20a6) in base 7. What is the total cost of the items in another currency \u201cANTI\u201d (\u20b3) in base 8?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["M224","M114","M340","M440"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>When the price of egg was raised by \u20a62 an egg, the number of eggs which can be bought for \u20a6120 is reduced by \u20a65. The present price of an egg is<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["\u20a66","\u20a67","\u20a68","\u20a610"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>How long will it take a sum of money invested at 8% simple interest to double the original sum?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["8 years","10.5 years","12 years","12.5 years"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>The journey from Lagos to Ibadan usually takes a motorist 1 hour 30 minutes. By increasing his average speed by 20km\/hr, the motorist saves 15 minutes. His usual speed, in km\/hr is<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["100","90","85","80"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>The smallest section of a rod which can be cut into exactly equal sections, each of either 30cm 0r 36cm in length is<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["90cm","180cm","360cm","540cm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>If x = 0.0012 + 0.00074 + 0.003174, what is the difference between x and 2 decimal places and x to 1 significant figure?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["0.01","0.0051","0.1","0.005"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>The angle of depression of two points A and B on a plane field from the top of a mast erected between A and B are 30\u00b0 and 45\u00b0 respectively. If A is westward of B, find \u2502AB\u2502 if the height of the mast is 15m from the field.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["15\u221a3m","5(3 - \u221a3)m","15(1 + \u221a3 )m","15(\u221a3 \u2212 1)m"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>The radius of a circle is given as 10cm subject to an error of 0.2cm. the error in the are of the circle is<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub>%","<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>50<\/sub>%","2%","4%"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>In a survey of 100 students in an institution, 80 students speak Yoruba, 22 speak Igbo, while 6 speak neither Igbo nor Yoruba. How many students speak Yoruba and Igbo.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["96","8","64","12"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>A bag contains 5 yellow balls, 6 green and 9 black balls. A ball is drawn from the bag. What is the probability that it is a black or yellow ball?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["<sup>7<\/sup>\/<sub>10<\/sub>","<sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>40<\/sub>","<sup>7<\/sup>\/<sub>20<\/sub>","<sup>49<\/sup>\/<sub>400<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>The expression a<sup>3<\/sup> + b<sup>3<\/sup> is equal to<\/b><\/p>","options":["(a<sup>2<\/sup> + b)(a \u2013 ab \u2013 b<sup>2<\/sup>)","(a + b)(a<sup>2<\/sup> - ab + b<sup>2<\/sup>)","(a \u2013 b<sup>2<\/sup>)(a<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 ab + b)","(a \u2013 b)(a<sup>2<\/sup> + ab + b<sup>2<\/sup>)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>A cylinder has height 4cm and base radius 5cm. its volume to 3 significant figure is<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["314.2cm<sup>2<\/sup>","31.42cm<sup>2<\/sup>","251.4cm<sup>2<\/sup>","251cm<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Find the value of P if the line joining (P, 4) and (6, -2) is perpendicular to the line joining (2, P) and (-1, 3).<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["4","6","3","zero"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Dividing 2x<sup>3<\/sup> \u2013 x<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 5x + 1 by x + 3 gives the remainder.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["-3","47","61","-47"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Let f(x) = 2x<sup>3<\/sup> \u2013 3x<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 5x + 6. If x \u2013 1 divides f(x) find the zeros of the function.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["1, 2, <sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","1, 2, -<sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","-1, 2, 3","1, -2, -<sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>The difference of two numbers is 10, while their product is 39. Find these numbers<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["-3 and 10 or 13 and 10","3 and -10 or 3 and 13","3 and -3 or 3 and 13","-3 and -13 or 13 and 3"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>The average age of x pupils in a class is 14 years 2 months. A pupil of 15 years 2 months joins the class and the average age is increased by one month. Find x.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["12","6","11","14"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>If the distance covered by a body in time t seconds is s = t<sup>3<\/sup> \u2013 6t<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 5t, what is its initial velocity?<\/b><\/p>","options":["0ms<sup>-1<\/sup>","-4ms<sup>-1<\/sup>","(3t \u2013 12t \u2013 5)ms<sup>-1<\/sup>","5ms<sup>-1<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>In a throw of a fair die the probability of obtaining an even number is<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["1","<sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>","<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Two fair coins are tossed simultaneously. What is the probability of obtaining at least 1 tail turns up?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub>","<sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub>","<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","1"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>One angle of a polygon has each of its angles as 160\u00b0. What is the number of sides of the polygon?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["18","36","9","20"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>One angle of an octagon is 100\u00b0 while the other sides are equal. Find each of these exterior angles.<\/b><\/p>","options":["80","60","140","40"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>The centre and radius of the circle with the equation x<sup>2<\/sup> + y<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 2x + 6y + 5 = 0 are respectively<\/b><\/p>","options":["(1, 3) and 5","(3, 1) and \u221a5","(1, -3) and \u221a5","(3, -1) and 5"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Solve: Log<sub>5<\/sub> 0.04\/[<span style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">Log<\/span><sub style=\"font-size: 10.5px;\">3<\/sub><span style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">&nbsp;<\/span><span style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">18&nbsp; -&nbsp;<\/span><span style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">Log<\/span><sub style=\"font-size: 10.5px;\">3<\/sub><span style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">&nbsp;<\/span><span style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">2<\/span><span style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">]<\/span><\/b><\/p>","options":["<sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>","-1","1","-<sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>When the expression pm<sup>2<\/sup> + qm + 1 is divided by (m \u2013 1), it has a remainder of&nbsp; 2. When&nbsp;<\/b><span style=\"font-weight: bolder; font-size: 0.875rem;\">divided by (m + 1), it has a remainder of&nbsp; 4<\/span><b style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">. Find p and q respectively.<\/b><\/p>","options":["2, 1","2, -1","-1, 2","1, 2"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>If \u03b1 and \u03b2 are the roots of the equation x<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 5x \u2013 7 = 0. \u03b1<sup>2<\/sup>\u03b2 + \u03b1\u03b2<sup>2<\/sup> is<\/b><\/p>","options":["35","-35","42","-42"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>If \u03b1 and \u03b2 are the roots of the equation 2x<sup>2<\/sup> + 7x + 3 = 0. Obtain the equation whose roots are <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>\u03b1<sup>2<\/sup><\/sub> and <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>\u03b2<sup>2<\/sup><\/sub><\/b><\/p>","options":["9x<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 37x + 4 = 0","4x<sup>2<\/sup> + 49x + 9 = 0","2x<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 7x + 3","3x<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 37x \u2013 2 = 0"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>If one root of the equation 27x<sup>2<\/sup> + bx + 8 = 0 is the square of the other. Find b<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["20","25","-30","-25"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>If log<sub>10<\/sub>2 = y, express log<sub>10<\/sub>12.5 in terms of y.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["2 \u2013 3y","2(1 \u2013 y)","2(1 + y)","2 + 3y"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Find the roots of x<sup>3<\/sup> \u2013 2x<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 5x + 6 = 0.<\/b><\/p>","options":["1, 3, -2","1, 2, -3","-1, -2, 3","-1, 2, 3"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Find the remainder when 3x<sup>3<\/sup> + 5x<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 11x + 4 is divided by x + 3<\/b><\/p>","options":["4","1","-1","-4"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>What factor is common to all the expressions x<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 x, 2x<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 1 and x<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 1?<\/b><\/p>","options":["x","x - 1","x + 1","no common factor"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>In class of 40 students, 32 offers Mathematics, 24 offer Physics and 4 offer neither Mathematics nor Physics. How many offer both Mathematics and Physics?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["4","16","20","8"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>The probability of a student passing any exam is <sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>&nbsp;If the student takes three exams, what is the probability that he will not pass any of them?<\/b><\/p>","options":["<sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>","<sup>4<\/sup>\/<sub>9<\/sub>","<sup>8<\/sup>\/<sub>27<\/sub>","<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>27<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Find the mean of the data: 7, -3, 4, -2, 5, -9, 4, 8, -6, 12.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["3","4","1","2"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Find the value of a if the line 2y \u2013 ax + 4 = 0 is perpendicular to the line y + <sup>x<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub> - 7 = 0<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["-4","4","8","-8"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>A hunter 1.6m tall, views a bird on top of a tree at an angle of 45 degrees. If the distance between the hunter and the tree is 10.4m, find the height of the tree.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["9.0m","12.0m","8.8m","10.4m"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>The sum of the interior angles of a polygon is 20 right angles. How many sides does the polygon have?<\/b><\/p>","options":["12","20","40","10"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>A bucket is 12cm in diameter at the top, 8cm in diameter at the bottom and 4cm deep. Calculate its volume.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["304 (<sup>\u03c0<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>) cm<sup>3<\/sup>","144 (<sup>\u03c0<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub>) cm<sup>3<\/sup>","128 (<sup>\u03c0<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>) cm<sup>3<\/sup>","72 (<sup>\u03c0<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>) cm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>If tan \u03b8 = <sup>4<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>&nbsp;calculate sin<sup>2<\/sup> \u03b8 \u2013 cos<sup>2<\/sup> \u03b8<\/b><\/p>","options":["<sup>16<\/sup>\/<sub>25<\/sub>","<sup>24<\/sup>\/<sub>25<\/sub>","<sup>7<\/sup>\/<sub>25<\/sub>","<sup>9<\/sup>\/<sub>25<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>The inverse function f(x) = 3x + 4 is<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["<sup>(x - 4)<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>","<sup>(x - 5)<\/sup>\/<sub>5<\/sub>","<sup>(x + 3)<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub>","<sup>(x + 4)<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>If the 9th term of an A.P. is five times the 5th term, find the relationship between a and d.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["2a + 2 = 0","3a + 5d = 0","a + 3d = 0","a + 2d = 0"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Evaluate \u222b sin 3x dx<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["<sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub> cos 3x + c","<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub> cos 3x + c","sup>-1<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub> cos 3x + c","<sup>-2<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub> cos 3x + c"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Find the derivative of y = sin<sup>2<\/sup> (5x) with respect to x.<\/b><\/p>","options":["10 sin 5x cos 5x","5 sin 5x cos 5x","2 sin 5x cos 5x","15 sin 5x cos 5x"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>A circle with radius 5cm has its radius increasing at the rate of 0.2 cm\/s. What will be the corresponding increase in the area?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["2\u03c0","5\u03c0","\u03c0","4\u03c0"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>The slope of the tangent to the curve y = 3x<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 2x + 5 at the point (1, 6) is<\/b><\/p>","options":["4","1","6","5"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>If dy\/dx = 2x \u2013 3 and y = 3 when x = 0, find y in terms of x.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["2x<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 3x","x<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 3x","x<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 3x - 3","x<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 3x + 3"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Evaluate: (0.21 x 0.072 x 0.00054) \u00f7 (0.006 x 1.68 x 0.063), correct to 4 s.f.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["0.01286","0.01285","0.1286","0.1285"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>If log 10 to base 8 = X, evaluate log 5 to base 8 in terms of X.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["(1\/2) X","X \u2013 (1\/4)","X \u2013 (1\/3)","X \u2013 (1\/2)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>A trader bought 100 oranges at 5 for N1.20, 20 oranges got spoilt and the remaining were sold at 4 for N1.50. Find the percentage gain or loss.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["30% gain","25% gain","30% loss","25% loss"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Factorize completely X<sup>2<\/sup> + 2XY + Y<sup>2<\/sup>2 + 3X + 3Y \u2013 18<\/b><\/p>","options":["(x + y + 6) (x + y + 3)","(x - y - 6) (x + y + 3)","(x - y + 6) (x - y - 3)","(x + y - 6) (x +y+3)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Tope bought X mangoes at N5.00 each and some apples at N4.00 each. If she bought twice as many apples as mangoes and spent at least N65.00 and at most N130.00, find the range of values of X.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["4 \u2264 X \u2264 5","5 \u2264 X \u2264 8","5 \u2264 X \u2264 10","8 \u2264 X \u2264 10"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Express 1\/(x<sup>3<\/sup> \u2013 1) in partial fraction.<\/b><\/p>","options":["1\/3 {(1\/x-1) \u2013 (x \u2013 2\/x<sup>2<\/sup>  \u2013 x + 1)}","1\/3 {(1\/x \u2013 1) \u2013 (x + 2\/x<sup>2<\/sup> + x + 1)}","1\/3 {(1\/x \u2013 1) \u2013 (x - 2\/x<sup>2<\/sup> + x + 1)}","1\/3 {(1\/x \u2013 1) \u2013 (x - 2\/x<sup>2<\/sup> - x - 1)}"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Divide 4x<sup>3<\/sup> \u2013 3x \u2013 1 by 2x \u2013 1<\/b><\/p>","options":["2x<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 x + 1","2x<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 x - 1","2x<sup>2<\/sup> + x + 1","2x<sup>2<\/sup> + x - 1"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>In \u2206MNO, MN = 6 units, MO = 4 units and NO = 12 units. If the angle bisector of N and M meets NO at P, calculate NP.<\/b><\/p>","options":["4.8 units","7.2 units","8.0 units","18.0 units"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>From a point P, the bearings of two points Q and R are 67\u00b0W and N23\u00b0E respectively. If the bearing of R from Q is N68\u00b0E and PQ = 150m, calculate PR.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["120m","140m","150m","160m"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>A two-digit number, say AB was mistakenly written as BA by an overworked student. Due to this error, the student was working with a number bigger in value, and its difference with the actual number is one less than the actual number. If the sum of the two digits is half a score. What is the actual number?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["43","34","73","37"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>A man wishes to keep his money in a savings deposit at 25% compound interest so that after three years he can buy a car for N150,000. How much does he need to deposit?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["N112,000.50","N96,000.00","N85,714.28","N76,800.00"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>If 314<sub>10<\/sub> \u2013 256<sub>7<\/sub> = 340<sub>x<\/sub>&nbsp;find x.<\/b><\/p>","options":["7","8","9","10"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>The third term of an A.P. is 4x \u2013 2y and the 9th term is 10x \u2013 8y. Find the common difference.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["19x \u2013 17y","8x \u2013 4y","x \u2013 y","2x"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>A trader realizes 10x \u2013 x<sup>2<\/sup> naira profit from the sale of x bags of corn. How many bags will give him the desired profit?<\/b><\/p>","options":["4","5","6","7"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Solve the inequality 2 \u2013 x &gt; x<sup>2<\/sup><\/b><\/p>","options":["x < -2 or x > 1","x > 2 or x < -1","-1 < x < 2","-2 < x < 1"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>If y = 2xcos2x \u2013 sin 2x, find dy\/dx when x = \u03c0\/4.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["\u03c0","-\u03c0","\u03c0\/2","\u2013 \u03c0\/2"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>If the volume of a hemisphere is increasing at a steady rate of 18 \u03c0 m\/s, at what rate is its radius changing when it is 6m?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["2.30 m\/s","2.00 m\/s","0.25 m\/s","0.20 m\/s"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>If the mean of the numbers 0, (x + 2), (3x + 6) and (4x + 8) is 4, find their mean deviation.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["0","2","3","4"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>In how many ways can the word MATHEMATICS be arranged?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["11!\/(9!2!)","11!\/(9!2!2!)","11!\/(2!2!2!)","11!\/(2!2!)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>The variance of x, 2x, 3x, 4x and 5x is<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["x\u221a2","2x<sup>2<\/sup>","x<sup>2<\/sup>","3x"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Find the sum of the range and the mode of the set of numbers: 10, 9, 10, 9, 8, 7, 7, 10, 8, 10, 8, 4, 6, 9, 10, 9, 10, 9, 7, 10, 6, 5.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["16","14","12","10"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>In how many ways can a delegation of 3 be chosen from among 5 men and 3 women, if at least one man and at least one woman must be included?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["15","28","30","45"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Simplify (\u221a0.7 + \u221a70)<sup>2<\/sup><\/b><\/p>","options":["84.7","70.7","217.7","168.7"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Find the range of these fractions: 1\/6, 1\/3, 3\/2, 2\/3, 8\/9 and 4\/3<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["3\/4","5\/6","7\/6","4\/3"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Find the number of ways of selecting 8 subjects from 12 subjects for an examination.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["490","495","496","498"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Teams P and Q are involved in a game of football. What is the probability that the game ends in a draw?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["2\/3","1\/2","1\/3","1\/4"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Find the rate of change of volume V of a sphere with respect to its radius r, when r = 1.<\/b><\/p>","options":["12 \u03c0","4 \u03c0","24 \u03c0","8 \u03c0"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Differentiate (2x + 5)<sup>2<\/sup>(x \u2013 4) with respect to x.<\/b><\/p>","options":["4 (2x + 5) (x \u2013 4)","4 (2x + 5) (x \u2013 3)","(2x + 5) (2x \u2013 13)","(2x + 5) (6 \u2013 11)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>P (-6, 1) and Q (6, 6) are the two ends of the diameter of a given circle. Calculate the radius.<\/b><\/p>","options":["6.5 units","13.0 units","3.5 units","7.0 units"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Find the number of sides of a regular polygon whose interior angle is twice the exterior angle.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["6","2","3","8"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>A sector of a circle of radius 7.2 cm which subtends an angle of 300\u00b0 at the center is used to form a cone. What is the radius of the base of the cone?<\/b><\/p>","options":["8 cm","6 cm","9 cm","7 cm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Solve the equations: m<sup>2<\/sup> + n<sup>2<\/sup> = 29, m + n = 7<\/b><\/p>","options":["(2,3) and (3,5)","(2,5) and (5,2)","(5,2) and (5,3)","(5,3) and (3,5)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Find the principal which amounts to N5,500 at a simple interest in 5 years at 2% per annum.<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["N4,900","N5,000","N4,700","N4,800"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>If x = (y\/2), evaluate {(x<sup>3<\/sup>\/y<sup>3<\/sup>) + (1\/2)} \u00f7 {(1\/2) \u2013 (x<sup>2<\/sup>\/y<sup>2<\/sup>)}<\/b><\/p>","options":["5\/8","5\/2","5\/4","5\/16"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Expression ax<sup>2<\/sup> + bx + c equals 5 at x = 1. If its derivative is 2x + 1, what re the values of a, b, c respectively?<\/b><\/p>","options":["1, 3, 1","1, 2, 1","2, 1, 1","1, 1, 3"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>If the minimum value of y = 1 + hx \u2013 3x<sup>2<\/sup> is 13, find h.<\/b><\/p>","options":["13","12","11","10"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>In a youth club with 94 members, 60 like modern music, and 50 like traditional music. The number of members who like both traditional and modern music is three times that of those who do not like any type of music. How many members like only one type of music?<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["8","24","62","86"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>Simplify 3(2<sup>n+1<\/sup>) \u2013 4(2<sup>n-1<\/sup>) - 2<sup>n+1<\/sup> \u2013 2<sup>n<\/sup><\/b><\/p>","options":["2<sup>n<\/sup>","2<sup>n-1<\/sup>","4","1\/4"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><b>If (x \u2013 1), (x + 1) and (x \u2013 2) are factors of the polynomial ax<sup>3<\/sup> + bx<sup>2<\/sup> + cx \u2013 1, find a, b, c in that order.<\/b><\/p>","options":["-1\/2, 1, 1\/2","1\/2, 1, 1\/2","1\/2, 1, -1\/2","1\/2, -1, 1\/2"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"null"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a bag, there are 8 identical balls in terms of size and shape, but 2 are white, 4 are black and 2 are yellow. If&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>balls are randomly drawn from the bag without&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>replacement, what is the probability that two balls drawn&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>from the bag, one is white and the other is black?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2\/7","6\/7","5\/7","1\/7"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the roots of the equation 6x<sup>2<\/sup>&nbsp;- 13x + 6 = 0<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2\/3, 3\/2","2\/3, -3\/2","-2\/3, -3\/2","2\/3, 3\/2"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A polynomial in x whose zeros are 2, -1&nbsp; and -7 is x3+ax2+bx -14 = 0. Find the values of a and b respectively?<\/strong><br><\/p>","options":["9, -6","-9, 6","6, -9","-6, 9"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>If y = (1 - 3x)<sup>3<\/sup>. find the value of dy\/dx at x = -2<\/strong><\/p>","options":["378","-324","-378","441"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Convert 366<sub>10<\/sub> to a binary number<\/strong><\/p>","options":["101110010","-101101110","10110111","-1011000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Given that x = 3, y = -2 and z = -1. Evaluate 3x<sup>2<\/sup>y<sup>2<\/sup>zx<sup>2<\/sup>y<sup>3<\/sup>z<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6776","9787","-7776","-9776"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Two ships A and B left port P on a bearings 053<\/strong><b>\u00b0<\/b><strong style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">&nbsp;and&nbsp;<\/strong><strong style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">113<\/strong><b>\u00b0&nbsp;<\/b><strong style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">respectively. If both ships steamed at 80km per&nbsp;<\/strong><strong style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">hour, how&nbsp;<\/strong><strong style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">far apart were they after 30 minutes?<\/strong><\/p>","options":[".-80km","60km","20km","40km"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>What are the coordinated of the midpoint of the line joining (-1, 6) and (5, -3)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(3, 4.5)","(2, 1.5)","(-3, 4.5)","(-2 ,- 1.5)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Determine <sup>2.813 x 1.063<\/sup>\/<sub>5.637<\/sub>&nbsp;&nbsp;x 10<sup>-1<\/sup>&nbsp;reducing each number to 2 s.f and leaving the answer in 2s.f.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.54","0.0054","0.0056","0.055"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Solve the inequality 2-x &gt; x<sup>2<\/sup><\/strong><\/p>","options":["x < 1 or x < -2","x > 2 or x < -1","x < -2 or x > 1","x > 2 or x < -2"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A fair coin is tossed ten times. What is the probability of getting at least two heads?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["513\/1024","615\/1024","968\/1024","1013\/1024"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man bought 220 mangoes at #5x. He sold each for 3x kobo and made a gain of #8. Find the value of x.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","5","10","6"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Calculate the sum to infinity of 1 + <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub> + <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>9<\/sub> + <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>27<\/sub> + .....<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.33","0.67","1.5","2.5"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Express tan&nbsp; (&nbsp;<\/strong><span style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">22<\/span><sup>1&nbsp;<s>\/<\/s><\/sup><sub>2<\/sub><strong style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">)&nbsp; in the surd form?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["+ \u221a2-2","l-\u221a2","+\u221a2-1",".+\u221a2+l"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>If sin (x-a)= cos (x+a), then tan x is ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":[".0.8","0.75","1.0","2.8"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A binary operation x is defined on R, the set of real&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>numbers by x *y = xy&nbsp;- 2,&nbsp; for all x,y E R. If x*(2*8) = 34, find x ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","4","9","10"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The equation 2x<sup>2<\/sup> + (k + 3) x + 2k = 0 has co-incident&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>roots. What is the constant k?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3 or 7","4 or 0","9 or l","9 or l"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The curve&nbsp; y = 2x<sup>2<\/sup> + x - 2 and the straight line y - 2x - 1 = 0&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>meet at the points whose x-values are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["<sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>  and  -1","-2  and  1","-<sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>and  1","2  and  -1"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the mean deviation of 5, 8, 3,7and 2.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0","2","5","10"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>An exponential sequence <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>, -<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub>, ........, -<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>256<\/sub> has n terms. Determine the value of n.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6","7","8","9"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<b>The volume of two similar solid cubes are 729cm<sup>3<\/sup> and 512cm<sup>3<\/sup>. Find the ratio of their lengths<\/b>","options":["4:3","9:7","9:7","9:8"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>In fig C, PR is a diameter, &lt;PRQ = (3x - 8), and&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>&lt;RPQ = (2y - 7), Express x in terms of y<\/strong><\/p>","options":["x=( 75 + 2y)\/3","x= (105 + 3y)\/2","x= (105 - 2y)\/3","x = (75 - 3y)\/2"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the mean deviation of 6,7,8,9, 10<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.2","1.5","2","8"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The matrix k is a 2x2 matrix given as k = <\/strong><b>\u23a1<\/b><strong style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">2,&nbsp; &nbsp; l<\/strong><b>\u23a4<\/b><strong style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">.&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong><strong style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">If&nbsp; &nbsp;I is a&nbsp;2x2 unit matrix, then k2 + I + k is?<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong><b>\u23a3<\/b><strong style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">&nbsp;3,&nbsp; 4<\/strong><b>\u23a6<\/b><\/p>","options":["{6, 3,  13, 20}","{9,  8,  22, 23}","{ 10,  7,  21,  24}","{1,   4,   21,  5}"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The line joining (p, 4) and (6, -2) is perpendicular to&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>the line joining (2, p) and (-1, 3). Find p<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6","3","4","0"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a regular polygon, each interior angle doubles its corresponding exterior angle. Find the number of sides of the polygon<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3","4","6","8"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The mean of the numbers 0, x+2, 3x+6 and4x+8 is&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>4. Find their mean deviation<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4","3","2","0"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"}]